# William Merrow

1118 Girard Street NW, Washington, DC 20009 – william.merrow@gmail.com – 603-568-0366 Portfolio: https://wmerrow.github.io/

# Summary

Information designer with proven experience leading research, analysis, and data visualization for clients on a range of public policy issues. Ability to approach projects from technical, creative, and project management standpoints. High attention to detail. Passion for clear and effective charts.

# **Skills**

research and data analysis data visualization design project management communication

#### **Tools**

R (ggplot2) Excel (VBA) Tableau Adobe Creative Suite Sketch HTML CSS

#### Education

**Tufts University**, B.A. 2011, *summa cum laude*, Phi Beta Kappa

Major: International Relations, Minor: Sociology; coursework in statistics and econometrics

School for International Training, Cochabamba, Bolivia, January to May 2010

#### Independent coursework:

Intermediate D3 for Data Visualization, Knight Center

Data Visualization with D3, Knight Center

Sketch 3: Mobile and Web Designs, Udemy

Front-end Web Developer Nanodegree, Udacity

# **Professional Experience**

## Data Analyst & Visualization Specialist

Graphicacy, Washington, DC September 2015 to present

- Lead research, analysis, and data visualization design for major think tank and nonprofit clients, using Adobe Illustrator, Excel, Tableau, and R to create clear and compelling graphics, working with researchers to ensure visualization design clearly communicates results and accomplishes goals
- Design websites, using Sketch to create high quality wireframes and comps in a deadline-based environment
- Lead data analysis projects, using R and Excel to manipulate and analyze large public datasets
- Manage large projects (\$100k+), managing developers and communicating with client to ensure project success
- Develop content on data visualization best practices, creating data visualization style guides, leading workshops, and representing Graphicacy at conferences and events
- Contribute to business development and strategic planning, securing new clients and helping to grow business

# Princeton in Latin America Fellow in Research & Evaluation The DREAM Project, Cabarete, Dominican Republic August 2014 to August 2015

- Managed and analyzed student data to assess education programs, identifying trends and ensuring data quality
- Led basic to advanced Excel workshops for all staff; trained managers in use of Salesforce and Tableau
- Led redesign, migration, and adoption of Salesforce database, creating objects, workflows, reports, and dashboards, using Tableau to visualize student data
- Managed data and reporting for USAID grant, leading to perfect score on audit of data system

#### Special Assistant to the President & CEO

InterAction, Washington, DC August 2011 to August 2014

# Language Skills:

Spanish - professional German - conversational

- Authored remarks, blogs, and articles for CEO, researching and writing on range of international development topics; published in 2012 Reality of Aid report on the role of corporations in foreign aid; coordinated drafting, editing, and copyediting of 42 policy briefs for flagship publication
- Coordinated data and communications for \$1.5b food security pledge by 30 international NGOs; prepared data for use in remarks of President Obama and Secretary Clinton
- Managed advocacy projects, analyzing legislative language and meeting with congressional staff; managed CEO-level taskforces on aid reform and corporations in international development
- Promoted to Senior Associate level (2012) and Coordinator level (2014); voted Best Team Player

## **Congressional Program Intern**

Inter-American Dialogue, Washington, DC *June to August 2011* 

#### Research Intern

Americans for Campaign Reform, Concord, NH *June to August 2010*